pa.gov 2017-06-29

# Privacy Policy & Disclaimers | PA.GOV

Thank you for visiting this Commonwealth of Pennsylvania website. Please read the following important information about the Commonwealth’s websites:

  * Privacy Policy
    * Information Collected
    * Public Disclosure
    * Access to User Profiles
    * Choice
    * Cookies
  * Disclaimers
    * External Linking Policy and Disclaimer
    * Information Disclaimer
    * Translation Disclaimer
    * Social Media Policy and Disclaimer
    * Contact Information

### PRIVACY POLICY

We are committed to maintaining your privacy. This policy addresses the collection, security and access to information that may be obtained through the use of our site. This policy covers the following topics:

  * Information Collected
  * Public Disclosure
  * Access to User Profiles
  * Choice
  * Cookies

#### INFORMATION COLLECTED

As part of standard Internet practice we collect the following information when you visit our sites:

  * Your domain name; for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private internet access account, or “yourschool.edu”, if you are connecting from a university domain;
  * Your IP address, a number automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site;
  * The pages you visit within the commonwealth’s site; and
  * The links made to other websites through this site.

This information is collected for statistical analysis using standard third-party software programs to create summary statistics. The statistics are used for the purpose of determining what information is of most and least interest to all visitors and identifying system performance or problem areas. This information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes. The Commonwealth does not sell information collected online. Any personally identifiable information (PII) that you voluntarily provide will be collected. PII may include an email address or any other information you submit via a website when completing an application, form, or survey online. The information collected, whether or not personally identifiable, is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and other graphic formats you send us. Information is retained in accordance with existing laws and other Commonwealth policies.  

#### PUBLIC DISCLOSURE

As a general rule, the Commonwealth does not disclose any personally identifiable information collected online except where you have given us permission, or where the information is public information under the Pennsylvania Right to Know Law 65 P.S. 67.101, et seq., or other applicable laws. Visitors should be aware that information collected by the Commonwealth on its websites may be subject to public disclosure if such information is a public record, or to other examination and inspection if the information is not otherwise protected.  

#### ACCESS TO USER PROFILES

Any personally identifiable information you enter in a user profile will be open and accessible to you for review and modification.  

#### CHOICE

You may decline participation in any activity that asks for information (i.e., surveys or emails). Your choice to not participate will have no effect on your ability to view information on the Commonwealth’s websites.  

#### COOKIES

We may customize your browsing experience by using “cookies” to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer. (Cookies are simple text files stored by your web browser and they provide a method of distinguishing among visitors to the websites.) You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer at any time by using any one of a number of widely available methods.

Commonwealth policy does not allow for the use of persistent cookies. Cookies created on your computer by using our websites do not contain personally identifiable information and do not compromise your privacy or security.  

### DISCLAIMERS

#### EXTERNAL LINKING POLICY AND DISCLAIMER

The information posted on Commonwealth websites may include hypertext links, or pointers, to information created and maintained by other public and/or private organizations (outside websites).

We only provide these links and pointers for your information and convenience. When you select a link to an outside website, you are leaving the Commonwealth site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of the outside website.

  * The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania **does not** control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness of information contained on an outside website.
  * The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania **does not** endorse the organizations sponsoring outside websites and does not endorse the views they express or the products/services they offer.
  * The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania **cannot** authorize the use of copyrighted materials contained in outside websites. Users must request such authorization from the sponsor of the outside website.
  * The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania **is not** responsible for transmissions users receive from outside websites.
  * The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania **cannot** guarantee that outside websites comply with accessibility requirements.

#### INFORMATION DISCLAIMER

Information provided on the Commonwealth’s websites is intended to allow the public immediate access to public information. While all attempts are made to provide accurate, current, and reliable information we recognize the possibility of human and/or mechanical error. Therefore, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, its employees, officers, and agencies expressly disclaim any warranty of the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of any information published by this system and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance upon the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of such information. Any person who relies upon such information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.

#### TRANSLATION DISCLAIMER

The PA.gov website is providing the “Google Translate” option to assist you in reading the PA.gov website in languages other than English.

Google Translate cannot translate all types of documents, and may not provide an exact translation. Anyone relying on information obtained from Google Translate does so at his or her own risk. The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania does not make any promises, assurances, or guarantees about the content of the translations, the specific functions of the Google Translate tool, or its reliability, availability, or ability to meet your needs.

The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, its officers, employees, and/or agents shall not be liable for damages or losses of any kind arising out of, or in connection with, the use of the Google Translate tool, including but not limited to, damages or losses caused by reliance upon the accuracy of translations, or damages incurred from the viewing, distributing, or copying of such materials.  

#### SOCIAL MEDIA POLICY AND DISCLAIMER

Commonwealth of Pennsylvania government agencies and government officials engage with Pennsylvanians through many online channels, including [PA.gov](http://www.pa.gov/), [governor.pa.gov](https://www.governor.pa.gov/), [agency websites](http://www.pa.gov/media/#social), and [social media](http://www.pa.gov/media/#social). We encourage the public to engage with the commonwealth through these channels and welcome all viewpoints. Please be aware that when engaging with the commonwealth over social media, you are agreeing to the following.

##### OFFICIAL SOCIAL MEDIA CHANNELS

A list of official Commonwealth of Pennsylvania government online channels [can be found on PA.gov](http://www.pa.gov/). The commonwealth is not responsible for non-official pages or content generated by users on those platforms.

##### TERMS AND CONDITIONS

The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania’s government social media pages are located within platforms such as Facebook and Twitter that have their own terms of services, privacy policies, and other rules to which users are subject when users visit those pages.

##### USER-GENERATED CONTENT

The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania monitors its government social media pages but is not responsible for content generated by users on those platforms. Comments and other content posted on those platforms may be subject to public disclosure.

The commonwealth’s individual social media pages also contain their own commenting policy statements and provisos which users are presumed to have read and understand in their use of the channels.

##### CONTACTING THE COMMONWEALTH

Social media is not considered an official channel for contacting Commonwealth of Pennsylvania agencies and officials. While the commonwealth at times responds to queries and comments on social media, staffing for that purpose is not 24/7. The commonwealth encourages users to follow instructions on how to officially contact government offices found on their individual websites. A list of official commonwealth websites and contact pages [can be found on PA.gov](http://www.pa.gov/media/#social).

Communications posted on the commonwealth’s social media pages will not be construed as satisfying requirements for legal notice or service, shall not be considered official public comment, and shall not be construed as an official request for records pursuant to the Right-to-Know Law.

##### INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY

The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania does not claim ownership of content users submit or make available on our social media pages. We only claim rights in what we write, post, or otherwise share.

We have intellectual property interests in everything we post or otherwise share (even though some of it may have come from other sources); our intellectual property is not in the public domain unless we specifically say so. In other words, if users want to use a logo, a video, a document, etc., users need to get our legal permission.

##### LINKS

The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania sometimes posts links to other public and/or private organizations on social media. A link does not constitute an endorsement of content, viewpoint, policies, products, or services of that web site. Once a user clicks a link to another website not maintained by the commonwealth, the user is subject to the terms and conditions of that website. Read our full [external linking policy and disclaimer on PA.gov](http://www.pa.gov/privacy-policy/#external-links).

### CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions or comments about the information presented in this page, you can contact the Commonwealth’s Office of Administration, Office for Information Technology as follows:

By Fax: 717-787-4523  
By Mail: 209 Finance Building, Harrisburg, PA 17120  
By Email: RA-ITCentral@pa.gov
